Guide to the M*A*S*H (television program) Scripts Collection
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
MASH (television program) scripts collection
1971-1982
MS 1404
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
4.5
(11 boxes)
The collection consists of scripts written for the television program "M*A*S*H". These scripts are the final draft copies used by Loretta Swit Holahan, who portrayed the character Margaret "Hot Lips" Houlihan for the entire run of the television series.
Holahan, Loretta Swit
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Gift of Loretta Swit Holahan, 1985.
Biographical / Historical
The "M*A*S*H" television program appeared on the CBS television network from 1971-1982. The program portrayed the daily activities of doctors and nurses serving in a Mobile Army Surgical Hospital (M*A*S*H) unit during the Korean War.
Arrangement
The collection is arranged in chronological order, by the copyright date which appears on the title page of each document.
Scope and Contents
The collection consists of the final versions of scripts used by Loretta Swit Holohan, in her role as Margaret "Hot Lips" Houlihan, on the television show "M*A*S*H." The collection contains scripts for all of the programs, including the pilot episode broadcast in 1971 and the final episode shown in 1982.
A small portion of the scripts contains annotations for last-minute changes in the dialogue. The scripts also contain stage directions for clothing, settings, and background views. The scripts are arranged in chronological order, by the copyright date which appears on the title page of each document.
The collection was donated to Yale University by Loretta Swit Holohan in 1985.
M*A*S*H (Television program); Television programs; Holahan, Loretta Swit
- Inventory
  - "M*A*S*H", 1971 November 17 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - "The Fighting 4077th", 1972 May 26 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - "To Market, To Market", 1972 May 31 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - "Chief Surgeon Who?", 1972 June 28 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - "Germ Warfare", 1972 July 18 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - "I Hate a Mystery", 1972 July 31 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - "Dear Dad...", 1972 July 31 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - "Requiem for a Lightweight", 1972 August 1 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - "Yankee Doodle Doctor", 1972 August 22 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - "Tuttle", 1972 November 8 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - "The Ringbanger", 1972 November 21 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - "Dear Dad...Again", 1972 November 22 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - "Sometimes You Hear the Bullet", 1972 December 4 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - "The Longjohn Flap", 1972 December 8 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - "Sticky Wicket", 1972 December 20 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - "Major Fred C. Dobbs", 1972 December 26 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - "The Army-Navy Game", 1973 January 2 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - "Ceasefire", 1973 January 23 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - "Showtime", 1973 January 29 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - "Divided We Stand", 1973 July 30 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - "Radar's Report", 1973 August 1 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - "5 O'clock Charlie", 1973 August 9 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - "L.I.P.", 1973 August 20 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - "Dr. Pierce and Mr. Hyde", 1973 August 20 (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - "Kim", 1973 August 31 (Box 2, Folder 25)
  - "The Trial of Henry Blake", 1973 September 18 (Box 2, Folder 26)
  - "Dear Dad...Three", 1973 September 19 (Box 2, Folder 27)
  - "The Sniper", 1973 October 3 (Box 2, Folder 28)
  - "Carry On, Hawkeye", 1973 October 11 (Box 2, Folder 29)
  - "Hot Lips and Empty Arms", 1973 November 6 (Box 2, Folder 30)
  - "Officers Only", 1973 November 12 (Box 2, Folder 31)
  - "Henry in Love", 1973 November 20 (Box 2, Folder 32)
  - "For Want of a Boot...", 1973 November 27 (Box 2, Folder 33)
  - "As You Were", 1973 December 14 (Box 2, Folder 34)
  - "Crisis", 1973 December 26 (Box 2, Folder 35)
  - "George", 1974 January 3 (Box 2, Folder 36)
  - "Mail Call", 1974 January 10 (Box 2, Folder 37)
  - "A Smattering of Intellignece", 1974 January 11 (Box 2, Folder 38)
  - "Rainbow Bridge", 1974 May 8 (Box 2, Folder 39)
  - "Life With Father", 1974 May 10 (Box 2, Folder 40)
  - "Springtime", 1974 May 14, 1974 May 16 (Box 2, Folder 41-42)
  - "Iron Guts Kelly", 1974 May 24 (Box 2, Folder 43)
  - "Payday", 1974 June 3 (Box 2, Folder 44)
  - "O.R.", 1974 June 12 (Box 2, Folder 45)
  - "The General Flipped at Dawn", 1974 June 13 (Box 2, Folder 46)
  - "Officer of the Day", 1974 June 17 (Box 2, Folder 47)
  - "There Is Nothing Like a Nurse", 1974 June 19 (Box 2, Folder 48)
  - "Check-up", 1974 July 26 (Box 3, Folder 49)
  - "Big Mac", 1974 August 7 (Box 3, Folder 50)
  - "Alcoholics Unanimous", 1974 August 26 (Box 3, Folder 51)
  - "House Arrest", 1974 August 28 (Box 3, Folder 52)
  - "Mad Dogs and Servicemen", 1974 September 3 (Box 3, Folder 53)
  - "The Consultant", 1974 September 6 (Box 3, Folder 54)
  - "Aid Station", 1974 September 16 (Box 3, Folder 55)
  - "Bombed", 1974 September 30 (Box 3, Folder 56)
  - "White Gold", 1974 October 2 (Box 3, Folder 57)
  - "Bulletin Board", 1974 October 21, 1974 October 25 (Box 3, Folder 58-59)
  - "Abyssinia, Henry", 1974 October 28 (Box 3, Folder 60)
  - "Change of Command", 1975 June 30 (Box 3, Folder 61)
  - "It Happened One Night", 1975 July 3 (Box 3, Folder 62)
  - "Of Moose and Men", 1975 July 10 (Box 3, Folder 63)
  - "Dear Mildred", 1975 July 18 (Box 3, Folder 64)
  - "Welcome to Korea", 1975 July 24 (Box 3, Folder 65)
  - "The Late Captain Pierce", 1975 August 4 (Box 3, Folder 66)
  - "Smilin' Jack", 1975 August 14 (Box 3, Folder 67)
  - "Dear Peggy", 1975 August 18 (Box 3, Folder 68)
  - "Hey, Doc", 1075 August 28 (Box 3, Folder 69)
  - "The Kids", 1975 September 4 (Box 3, Folder 70)
  - "Quo Vadis, Captain Chandler?", 1975 September 22 (Box 3, Folder 71)
  - "Soldier of the Month", 1975 October 2 (Box 3, Folder 72)
  - "Dear Ma", 1975 October 8 (Box 3, Folder 73)
  - "Deluge", 1975 October 14 (Box 4, Folder 74)
  - "The Gun", 1975 October 20 (Box 4, Folder 75)
  - "Mail Call Again", 1975 October 27 (Box 4, Folder 76)
  - "The Price of Tomato Juice", 1975 October 31 (Box 4, Folder 77)
  - "The Interview", 1975 December 15 (Box 4, Folder 78)
  - "Mulcahy's War", 1976 June 3 (Box 4, Folder 79)
  - "Margaret's Engagement", 1976 June 23 (Box 4, Folder 80)
  - "Lt. Radar O'Reilly", 1976 June 25 (Box 4, Folder 81)
  - "The General's Practitioner", 1976 June 28 (Box 4, Folder 82)
  - "Ping Pong", 1976 June 29 (Box 4, Folder 83)
  - "Bug Out", 1976 July 6 (Box 4, Folder 84)
  - "Hawk's Nightmare", 1976 July 20 (Box 4, Folder 85)
  - "The Abduction of Margaret Houlihan", 1976 July 21 (Box 4, Folder 86)
  - "Out of Sight, Out of Mind", 1976 July 29 (Box 4, Folder 87)
  - "The Colonel's Horse", 1976 August 16 (Box 4, Folder 88)
  - "The Nurses", 1976 August 19 (Box 4, Folder 89)
  - "Dear Sigmund", 1976 September 3 (Box 4, Folder 90)
  - "The Most Unforgettable Characters", 1976 September 10 (Box 4, Folder 91)
  - "Hawkeye Get Your Gun", 1976 September 15 (Box 4, Folder 92)
  - "Exorcism", 1976 October 15 (Box 4, Folder 93)
  - "The Korean Surgeon", 1976 October 7 (Box 4, Folder 94)
  - "Margaret's Marriage", 1976 October 14 (Box 4, Folder 95)
  - "Souvenirs", 1976 October 15 (Box 5, Folder 96)
  - "End Run", 1976 October 15 (Box 5, Folder 97)
  - "Hanky Panky", 1976 November 16 (Box 5, Folder 98)
  - "38 Across", 1976 November 18, 1976 November 26 (Box 5, Folder 99-100)
  - "Hepatitis", 1976 December 9 (Box 5, Folder 101)
  - "Movie Tonight", 1976 December 15 (Box 5, Folder 102)
  - "Post-Op", 1976 December 17 (Box 5, Folder 103)
  - "Last Laugh", 1977 June 2 (Box 5, Folder 104)
  - "Fade Out, Fade In", 1977 June 16 (Box 5, Folder 105)
  - "Images", 1977 June 17 (Box 5, Folder 106)
  - "Fallen Idol", 1977 July 5 (Box 5, Folder 107)
  - "War of Nerves", 1977 July 8 (Box 5, Folder 108)
  - "The Winchester Tapes", 1977 July 27 (Box 5, Folder 109)
  - "The Light that Failed", 1977 August 18 (Box 5, Folder 110)
  - "The Grim Reaper", 1977 September 1 (Box 5, Folder 111)
  - "Tea and Empathy", 1977 September 2 (Box 5, Folder 112)
  - "In Love and War", 1977 September 15 (Box 5, Folder 113)
  - "The Mash Olympics", 1977 September 16 (Box 5, Folder 114)
  - "Change Day", 1977 September 19 (Box 5, Folder 115)
  - "Patent 4077", 1977 October 3 (Box 5, Folder 116)
  - "The Smell of Music", 1977 October 11 (Box 6, Folder 117)
  - "Comrades in Arms (Part 1)", 1977 October 19 (Box 6, Folder 118)
  - "The Merchant of Korea", 1977 October 20 (Box 6, Folder 119)
  - "Comrades in Arms (Part 2)", 1977 October 21 (Box 6, Folder 120)
  - "What's Up, Doc?", 1977 November 7 (Box 6, Folder 121)
  - "Potter's Retirement", 1977 November 16 (Box 6, Folder 122)
  - "Mail Call Three", 1977 November 28 (Box 6, Folder 123)
  - "Major Topper", 1977 December 8 (Box 6, Folder 124)
  - "Your Hit Parade", 1977 December 19 (Box 6, Folder 125)
  - "Temporary Duty", 1977 December 22 (Box 6, Folder 126)
  - "Lil", 1978 June 27 (Box 6, Folder 127)
  - "B.J. Papa San", 1978 July 17 (Box 6, Folder 128)
  - "Peace On Us", 1978 July 17 (Box 6, Folder 129)
  - "Commander Pierce", 1978 July 24 (Box 6, Folder 130)
  - "Baby, It's Cold Outside", 1978 July 28 (Box 6, Folder 131)
  - "The Billfold Syndrome", 1978 August 4 (Box 6, Folder 132)
  - "They Call the Wind Korea", 1978 August 22 (Box 6, Folder 133)
  - "Our Finest Hour", 1978 September 5 (Box 6, Folder 134)
  - "None Like It Hot", 1978 September 11 (Box 6, Folder 135)
  - "Out of Gas", 1978 September 15 (Box 6, Folder 136)
  - "Major Ego", 1978 September 22 (Box 6, Folder 137)
  - "Dear Comrade", 1978 September 29 (Box 7, Folder 138)
  - "An Eye for a Tooth", 1978 October 2 (Box 7, Folder 139)
  - "Point of View", 1978 October 18 (Box 7, Folder 140)
  - "Preventive Medicine", 1978 October 23 (Box 7, Folder 141)
  - "Dear Sis", 1978 October 25 (Box 7, Folder 142)
  - "The Young and the Restless", 1978 November 27 (Box 7, Folder 143)
  - "Ain't Love Grand", 1978 December 1 (Box 7, Folder 144)
  - "Cave", 1978 December 8 (Box 7, Folder 145)
  - "The Party", 1978 December 18 (Box 7, Folder 146)
  - "A Night At Rosie's", 1979 January 5 (Box 7, Folder 147)
  - "Guerilla My Dreams", 1979 June 22 (Box 7, Folder 148)
  - "Too Many Cooks", 1979 July 9 (Box 7, Folder 149)
  - "Are You Now, Margaret?", 1979 July 13 (Box 7, Folder 150)
  - "Period of Adjustment", 1979 July 16 (Box 7, Folder 151)
  - "Private Finance", 1979 July 23 (Box 7, Folder 152)
  - "Mr. and Mrs. Who?", 1979 August 9 (Box 7, Folder 153)
  - "The Yalu Brick Road", 1979 August 17 (Box 7, Folder 154)
  - "Life Time", 1979 August 24 (Box 7, Folder 155)
  - "Nurse Doctor", 1979 August 28 (Box 7, Folder 156)
  - Good-bye Radar -- Part Two, 1979 September 7 (Box 7, Folder 157)
  - Good-bye Radar -- Part One, 1979 September 10 (Box 7, Folder 158)
  - "Dreams", 1979 September 18 (Box 8, Folder 159)
  - "Dear Uncle Abdul", 1979 October 9 (Box 8, Folder 160)
  - "Heal Thyself", 1979 November 5 (Box 8, Folder 161)
  - "Yessir, That's Our Baby", 1979 November 9 (Box 8, Folder 162)
  - "Morale Victory", 1979 November 26 (Box 8, Folder 163)
  - "Old Soldiers", 1979 November 30 (Box 8, Folder 164)
  - "Lend a Hand", 1979 December 13 (Box 8, Folder 165)
  - "Goodbye, Cruel World", 1979 December 21 (Box 8, Folder 166)
  - "War Correspondent", 1980 January 14 (Box 8, Folder 167)
  - "Back Pay", 1980 January 18 (Box 8, Folder 168)
  - "Letters", 1980 June 26 (Box 8, Folder 169)
  - "No Sweat", 1980 July 2 (Box 8, Folder 170)
  - "The Best of Enemies", 1980 July 7 (Box 8, Folder 171)
  - "Cementing Relationships", 1980 July 14 (Box 8, Folder 172)
  - "Tell It to the Marines", 1980 July 17 (Box 8, Folder 173)
  - "A War For All Seasons", 1980 August 8 (Box 8, Folder 174)
  - "That's Show Biz (Part One)", 1980 August 15 (Box 8, Folder 175)
  - "That's Show Biz (Part Two)", 1980 August 28 (Box 8, Folder 176)
  - "Father's Day", 1980 August 29 (Box 8, Folder 177)
  - "Your Retention, Please", 1980 September 12 (Box 8, Folder 178)
  - "Death Takes the Holiday", 1980 November 3 (Box 8, Folder 179)
  - "Death Takes A Holiday", 1980 November 3 (Box 9, Folder 180)
  - "Depressing News", 1980 November 21 (Box 9, Folder 181)
  - "Operation Friendship", 1980 December 5 (Box 9, Folder 182)
  - "No Laughing Matter", 1980 December 12 (Box 9, Folder 183)
  - "Oh, How We Danced", 1980 December 18 (Box 9, Folder 184)
  - "Bottoms Up", 1980 December 30 (Box 9, Folder 185)
  - "The Red/White Blues", 1981 January 21 (Box 9, Folder 186)
  - "Bless You, Hawkeye", 1981 January 23 (Box 9, Folder 187)
  - "The Life You Save", 1981 January 30 (Box 9, Folder 188)
  - "Blood Brothers", 1981 February 27 (Box 9, Folder 189)
  - "The Foresight Saga", 1981 March 12 (Box 9, Folder 190)
  - "Identity Crisis", 1981 March 18 (Box 9, Folder 191)
  - "Rumor at the Top", 1981 March 26 (Box 9, Folder 192)
  - "Communication Breakdown", 1981 October 1 (Box 9, Folder 193)
  - "Give 'Em Hell, Hawkeye", 1981 October 9 (Box 9, Folder 194)
  - "The Tooth Shall Set You Free, 1981 October 16 (Box 9, Folder 195)
  - "Wheelers and Dealers", 1981 October 19 (Box 9, Folder 196)
  - "Snap Judgement", 1981 November 2 (Box 9, Folder 197)
  - "Snappier Judgement", 1981 November 3 (Box 9, Folder 198)
  - "'Twas the Day After Christmas", 1981 November 6 (Box 9, Folder 199)
  - Follies of the Living--Concerns of the Dead, 1981 November 20. (Box 9, Folder 200)
  - "Blood and Guts", 1981 November 27 (Box 10, Folder 201)
  - "The Birthday Girls", 1981 December 1 (Box 10, Folder 202)
  - "A Holy Mess", 1981 December 14 (Box 10, Folder 203)
  - "Where There's a Will, There's a War", 1982 January 11 (Box 10, Folder 204)
  - "Pressure Points", 1982 January 12 (Box 10, Folder 205)
  - "Heroes", 1982 February 3 (Box 10, Folder 206)
  - "Sons and Bowlers", 1982 February 10 (Box 10, Folder 207)
  - "That Darn Kid", 1982 March 8 (Box 10, Folder 208)
  - "The Moon Is Not Blue", 1982 March 15 (Box 10, Folder 209)
  - "Hey, Look Me Over", 1982 March 22 (Box 10, Folder 210)
  - "Foreign Affairs", 1982 April 2 (Box 10, Folder 211)
  - "Settling Debts", 1982 April 5 (Box 10, Folder 212)
  - "The Joker Is Wild", 1982 April 12, 1982 April 19 (Box 10, Folder 213-214)
  - "Trick or Treatment", 1982 August 20 (Box 10, Folder 215)
  - "Bombshells", 1982 August 25 (Box 10, Folder 216)
  - "Run For the Money", 1982 August 31 (Box 10, Folder 217)
  - "Goodbye, Farewell, and Amen", 1982 September 7 (Box 10, Folder 218)
  - "Goodbye, Farewell, and Amen", 1982 September 16 (Box 11, Folder 219)
  - "Friends and Enemies", 1982 September 20 (Box 11, Folder 220)
  - "U.N. The Night and The Music", 1982 November 8 (Box 11, Folder 221)
  - "Strange Bedfellows", 1982 November 19 (Box 11, Folder 222)
  - "Say No More", 1982 November 30 (Box 11, Folder 223)
  - "Give and Take", 1982 December 6 (Box 11, Folder 224)
  - "As Time Goes By", 1982 December 20 (Box 11, Folder 225)